sunnewsnetwork.ca 2014-12-27

# Canada's Home for Hard News and Straight Talk

Privacy Policy

### Protection and respect of your privacy 

Sun News Network appreciates the concerns you may have with respect to the circulation of personal information on the Internet and, with your collaboration, wishes to address these issues. This is why we feel it is important that you fully understand the type of information we collect from you when visiting our website along with its intended use. 

Please read the following sections carefully. We also strongly suggest that you refer to this section periodically for changes or updates. Please be assured that the Sun News Network will not collect any personal information without your prior consent or knowledge. 

### The collection and processing of personal information

The collection and processing of personal information takes place under very precise conditions and at specific times. For example, when participating in online contests, you are required to enter your name, postal address, e-mail and other personal information by filling out an online form. From time to time, The Sun News Network also solicits online reader comments on various issues and topics. For the comments to be accepted, the Sun News Network requires that you submit your full name and city, along with any relevant comments and information, for potential publication online or in the print version of the newspaper. 

The Sun News Network also accepts written letters online. When you send a letter to the Sun News Network, you are consenting to the letter being published, along with your name and city. Please be advised that after you submit a letter, the Sun News Network owns the content of this letter and may republish it at any time. 

At these very specific times, the information that you submit will be processed and be subject to a host of data collection practices including saving, storing, editing, detailing, archiving and destruction. 

The Sun News Network also provides, within reasonable limits, means to verify the accuracy and to update your personal information. As well, on certain online forms, the Sun News Network may ask you if you wish to receive information on other services, contests or news about the Sun News Network and its partners. You are always given the option to decline such offers or to end your subscription to a previously requested service. 

The length of time the Sun News Network retains your personal information will vary depending upon the rules and requirements of each individual contest, promotion, or activity. 

It is important to note that the Sun News Network will never disclose your personal information with sponsors, advertisers, partners and other clients without your consent or without providing you with an opportunity to opt out. If we ever request information for another purpose, you will be automatically and explicitly informed at the time such information is requested. 

We will never disclose any personal information to parties outside of the Sun News Network without giving you an opportunity to opt out or without your explicit prior consent. Furthermore, all personal information collected by the Sun News Network is stored in server sectors that are inaccessible to the public. 

Despite the above, at any time, you may request that the Sun News Network end its use or planned use of your personal information. Doing so may disentitle you to participate in contests. 

In addition, the Sun News Network may disclose your personal information: upon request by a legal authority or in good faith when such action is deemed necessary (a) in order to abide by applicable laws or regulations or to intervene in a lawsuit against the Sun News Network; (b) in order to protect or defend the legal or property rights of the Sun News Network or those of its users; and (c) to intervene, under extreme circumstances, in order to protect the personal safety of Sun News Network users or the safety of the general public. 

### Be careful! 

The Sun News Network may contain links to third-party Web sites; these are provided solely for your convenience. Clicking on these links will take you outside of the Sun News Network. Please be advised that the Sun News Network has no control over these third-party sites and, while the Sun News Network may feature such links, the Sun News Network will not, at any time, accept liability for these sites. Consequently, personal information that you provide to a Web site outside of the Sun News Network is subject to the privacy protection policies of the given third-party site. In the event of abuse by such sites, the Sun News Network cannot, at any time, be held responsible. Therefore, we strongly urge you to carefully read the privacy protection policies of all third-party sites you choose to enter. 

We also wish to inform you that the risks associated with the supplying of personal information in a chat room, via e-mail or on a Web-based message board are not covered by our privacy protection policy; thus, you must be extremely careful if you choose to supply personal information through these means. You are submitting this information at your own risk. Indeed, this information may be collected and used by third parties without your prior consent. In other words, if you choose to provide personal information online and this information is available to the public, you may, eventually, receive unsolicited e-mail from third parties. The Sun News Network declines all responsibility in this regard. We urge you to remain cautious and vigilant, at all times, on the Internet. 

### Security 

The Sun News Network has set up security measures to protect you from the loss or unauthorized use of your supplied personal information. As well, our Sun News Network servers are equipped with firewall technology. Despite these measures, and given that no technology is foolproof, we must advise you that there will always remain a certain amount of risk and that your personal information may be disclosed, without your consent, unintentionally, and without fault on the part of the Sun News Network. The Sun News Network declines any responsibility in the event that such confidential information is disclosed, unless caused by negligence on the part of the Sun News Network. 

### Protection of children and teens on the Internet 

Children and teenagers are increasingly using the Internet and discovering its many advantages. However, as is the case in many other environments, their greater vulnerability may be targeted for crime and exploitation. This is why we urge you to monitor the Internet use of your children and teenagers and provide them with advice on security and recommendations based on common sense. Such measures will often prevent your children and teenagers from being exposed to offensive content, or from becoming victims of harassment or other criminal acts. 

To reduce these risks, as a parent, you should exercise a reasonable amount of supervision of Internet use by your children and teenagers. They should be told to never give out their personal information, such as their name, address or phone number, on any Internet forum. 

It is also important that children and teenagers be encouraged to share their concerns with you in the event that they receive disturbing or provocative messages. 

These recommendations will help your children and teenagers surf the Internet in an informed fashion and allow you to ensure that they fully benefit from the learning and development possibilities that exist online. 

### "Cookies" 

### What is a cookie? 

"Cookies" are little bits of information that are sent to your computer when you visit a Web site. They are saved, either temporarily or permanently, on your hard drive, leaving a trace of your passage. The information can include such things as the date and time of your last visit, a given answer to an online question, personal information, etc. Cookies can also enhance your Web experience by recording your navigation preferences for a given Web site. 

The use of cookies on the Web has become standard practice. Most Internet browsers will accept them by default. If you so choose, you may, at any time, change your parameters to disallow the use of cookies. However, in doing so, you will be unable to access the full features of certain sites. 

It should be noted that the actual cookie files stored on your hard drive are harmless. They may be read and deleted at any time. Thus, you always have complete control. 

### The use of cookies on Sunnewsnetwork.ca 

The Sun News Network uses cookies to monitor traffic, anonymously, on its Web sites. It allows us to estimate the size of our audience. 

Each visitor is assigned a unique cookie, for a temporary period of less than 24 hours` that allows us to determine the total number of repeat visits to the Sun News Network. 

While the information cannot be used to identify a visitor, cookies provide important data for our marketing department. Indeed, this information enables us to inform our sponsors of the total number of visitors for each of our sites and the length of each visit. In turn, it allows our sponsors to estimate or measure the probable or actual impact of their ads. It also allows us to determine our ad rates. While this information helps our sponsors buy ad space, it does not allow them to identify you individually. 

### Facebook

Third parties may use cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies to collect or receive information from this website and elsewhere on the internet and use that information to provide measurement services and target ads. You can opt-out of the collection and use of information for ad targeting. You may exercise that option [here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices).

### Twitter

We work with Twitter to bring you more useful and interesting advertising content. We may do this based on information that we share with Twitter. We hope that this increases the usefulness of Twitter Ads for you. If you do not want Twitter to tailor ads based on our this information, you can uncheck the box next to "Promoted content" in your [account settings](https://twitter.com/settings/security) at any time.

### Google Adwords

We use Remarketing with Google Adwords. Third-party vendors, including Google, may show our ads on sites across the Internet. We use cookies to optimize ads based on your past visits to our website. To opt-out from Google's remarketing program, please [ edit your Google Ad Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).

We hope that this information has provided you with a better understanding of our strict privacy protection policies. Please note that the Sun News Network reserves the right to modify these policies at any time. Thus, we invite you to periodically consult this section for possible updates and changes.
